Uh, scientists moved the South Pole, and
they're going to do it again. In 1911, a
team of Norwegian explorers planted a
flag at the southernmost point in the
world. They were racing a British team
that was pretty bummed to lose. But
today, that marker is not at the South
Pole. In fact, it's nearly 2 km from its
original point. Not because they moved
it, and not because the geographic South
Pole moved, but because it's on the
Antarctic ice sheet. And this ice flows.
Right here, it's moving in that
direction. It's propelled by gravity,
because this is a lot of ice. On
average, the Antarctic ice sheet is over
2 km thick. And that's a lot of pressure
on the lower layers. Because of this,
our marker moves about 10 m every year.
So, every January, scientists gather
together and move it back. It's not a
race, but an international celebration
[music] to set the pole right again.
But, this is not the magnetic South
Pole. If you want to know where that is,
subscribe.